KIA ORA, I AM

TISHA NAICKER.

2ND YEAR SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am in my third year of a Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) degree specialising in Software at the University of Auckland. My love and incredible passion for coding have led me to look for internship opportunities that utilise knowledge specific to my software engineering career. A little bit about me, I enjoy being creative through drawing and painting, and I would go to an escape room regularly if I could because I love problem-solving to escape them!

TECHNICAL SKILLS

I am proficient in Java, C, HTML, CSS, and MATLAB programming languages. I am familiar with Git, Collaborate Git, and GitHub as version control systems. Here are a few projects I have done:

- With Java, through a group project, we created a game with a GUI using JavaFX. The game was similar to the Quick, Draw Google game but with our own spin to it, hence it used Machine Learning to do predictions. This game was fully fledged with animations, creative design, game modes, badges, scores, and user profiles. We used json files to store data. We iteratively created this project based on client requirements and design meetings. Another Java project I did was create the game Black Jack where I used Factory and Strategy patterns for the bots and dealer. I also incorporated Artificial Intelligence by changing the dealer strategy in runtime based on player scores. I also created data structures and algorithms using Java such as Linked List, Stacks, and Queues, and used this to create Breadth First Search and Depth First Search. In all these projects I used Object Orientated Programming principles.
- C project where I created the Container Yard game effectively and efficiently. The game is where a container is stuck between other containers of different lengths and orientations and the objective is to take it out.
- With HTML and CSS I have created my website portfolio (linked below) and multiple websites in high school where I creatively designed wireframes, and developed and iterated my web design and functionality.
- MATLAB project about Visual Cryptography where I successfully encoded and decoded hidden messages in an image.

WORK EXPERIENCE

STUDENT TRAINING IN ENGINEERING PROGRAM INTERN | GOOGLE, SYDNEY

NOV 2022 - PRESENT

- Collaboratively worked on a FrontEnd project through pair programming.
- Consistently using the developer workflow to effectively improve the project.
- Participating in various team meetings to get hands-on experience in corporate culture and processes.
- Actively communicating with UX and Software Engineers to gain feedback and ensure the project has the end-users in mind.

SALES ASSISTANT | SMIGGLE, MANUKAU

OCT 2020 - FEB 2022

- Ensured I used excellent customer service skills such as welcoming, being a good listener to their needs, interests and always doing right by them.
- Efficiently and effectively met average transaction value and unit per transaction goals.

TUTOR | NUMBERWORK'NWORDS, HOWICK

OCT 2020 - DEC 2020

- Successfully tutored students ranging from primary to high school.
- Actively provided a set of tools, strategies and deeper understanding to improve their numeracy skills.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (HONOURS) SPECIALISING IN SOFTWARE

University of Auckland | Jan 2021 - Present (Graduation Year: 2024)

- Cumulative GPA of 8.42
- Part II: A+ for Object-Oriented Programming, A+ for Software Engineering Theory, A+ for Computer Engineering, A+ for Mathematical Modelling 2
- Part I: A+ for Introduction to Engineering Computation and Software Development

TISHA NAICKER

2ND YEAR SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Worley Professional Engineering Scholarship Recipient (2022)
- University of Auckland Top Achiever Scholarship (2021)
- Botany Downs Secondary College DUX (2020)

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Critical Thinking: My Engineering degree and the subjects I took in high school required a high level of critical thinking, such as analysing and problem-solving.
- Creativity: My favourite hobbies are art visual, digital, and dancing.
- · Teamwork: My prior job was heavily team-focused, and my past leadership roles in school have all been team-oriented.
- Communication: Growing up in church and having leadership roles in school has equipped me to build connections with people from various demographics.
- IT skills: I completed four years of Digital Technology in school, where most of my grades were excellences.
- Organisation: My grades are a product of being highly organised with my study habits and techniques.
- · Proficient in MS Office.
- Full License Driver

CO-CURRICULAR EXPERIENCE

In high school, I was in a leadership role where I was responsible for running and organising assemblies as well as being in charge of the academic committee. I participated in Indian and African dance, played Netball, mentored a student through COVID, and was involved in the math, outreach, and environmental committees. In church, I am part of the technology and creative team where I am in charge of audio and visual some Sundays and I have helped with mentoring young people.

INTERESTS

In my spare time, I love to draw, paint, and do digital art! I really enjoy making handcrafted keepsakes, so these are my favourite outlets to do so. I love my Fijian Indian culture and embrace it by giving importance to staying connected to my cultural roots such as by speaking Hindi. Being a woman in engineering can be hard but I am enormously proud to be part of that minority, so I go to various Women in Engineering events to meet individuals like me! I am also heavily involved in my c3 church community and actively do volunteer work as a part of that.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

I am bilingual, so I am fluent in Hindi and English! Hindi being my native language.

REFEREES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST



https://tnai255.github.io/TishaNaickerPortfolio/







